Finding Aid for Wellness HIV/AIDS Services records, 1986-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wellness HIV/AIDS Services records 1986-1999
Wellness HIV/AIDS Services.
2.5 linear feet
0714 Bj 2
Flint, Michigan-based HIV/AIDS services organization; board of directors minutes, administrative and topical files, and materials collected from other peer organizations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the organization (donor no. 9780 ) in September 2006.
The record group is open without restriction; access to the records does require the researcher to sign a statement agreeing to preserve the confidentiality of names mentioned in the files.
Established in January 1986, the Wellness HIV/AIDS Services organization grew out of the Flint AIDS Task Force. The purpose of the organization was to assist (through various services) in the care of people affected by HIV/AIDS and to promote education and prevention in the community. Some of the specific services provided by Wellness included anonymous HIV testing, counseling and case management, support groups for persons affected or infected by HIV or AIDS, and other miscellaneous assistance activities. Wellness HIV/AIDS Services served the people of Genesee, Lapeer, and Shiawassee counties.
The Wellness HIV/AIDS Services record group consists of the following series: Board of Directors files; Administrative and Topical files; and Related Organizations. Included are minutes and documents of the organization's board of directors, grant applications files, training and education materials, planning documents for HIV prevention initiatives, and materials received from other AIDS/HIV organizations.
Subjects:
Wellness HIV/AIDS Services.; AIDS (Disease)--Patients--Services for--Michigan.; HIV-positive persons--Services for--Michigan.; Wellness Networks (Organization)
- Board of Directors files
  - Minutes and discussion documents, 1986-1999, 19 folders (Box 1)
    (lacking 1996)
  - Board of Directors Retreat materials, March 1998 (Box 1)
- Administrative and Topical files
  - Grants (Box 2)
    - Community Foundation of Greater Flint, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
    - Flint Area Health Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Junior League of Flint, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Mott Children's Health Center, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Project for Urban and Regional Affairs, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
    - Special Office on AIDS Prevention (SOAP), 1987-1990 (Box 2)
  - Prevention
    - GLS (Genesee, Lapeer, Shiawassee) Community HIV Prevention Planning Group, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
    - Region VI Community Planning Group for HIV Prevention, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
    - Region VI HIV Comprehensive AIDS Resources Emergency Consortium, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
    - Statewide Community Planning Group for HIV Prevention, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Training and education
    - Training manual (Box 2)
    - Fundamentals of HIV Prevention Counseling (Box 2)
    - Resource materials
      - Section I: Basics of HIV/AIDS (Box 2)
      - Section II: HIV Testing; Section III: Legislation; Section IV: Psychosocial Issues (Box 2)
      - Section V: Issues for Populations Especially Affected by the Epidemic (Box 2)
      - Section VI: Prevention and Risk Reduction (Box 2)
      - Section VII: Glossary of HIV and AID Related Terminology (Box 2)
    - Other informational materials (Box 2)
- Related Organizations
  - Advisory Group on New Model for Community Organization, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Walk Michigan, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Battle Creek Community AIDS Resource and Education Services, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - HIV/AIDS Alliance of Michigan, 1995-1999, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Kalamazoo AIDS Resource Education Services, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Michigan's Persons Living with HIV/AIDS Task Force, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Planned Parenthood of East Central Michigan, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Southeastern Michigan HIV/AIDS Council, the Region I HIV Care Consortia, grant application submitted to the Michigan Department of Community Health, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Statewide HIV/AIDS Care Council
    - New Membership Portfolio (Box 3)
    - Policy and practices documents, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Transition House, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Wellness Network, Inc.
    - Detroit, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
    - Huron Valley (Box 3)
    - Traverse City, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Brochures (Box 3)